Draper Corporation Glass Plate Negatives 6612 GPN
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series A: 5 x 7 inch negatives.
  - Girls race, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 811)
    Negative no.A811. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a group of girls (well over a dozen) participating in a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. Some spectators can be glimpsed in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 811 for print of this negative.
  - Men's potato race, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 812)
    Negative no.A812. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a group of men participating in a potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The idea is probably to be the first to fill your box (seen on the ground on the left) with potatoes. Most of the potato races at Draper Company events involved women or girls, but this one features men. Some spectators can be glimpsed in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 812 for print of this negative.
  - Start of quarter-mile race, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 814)
    Negative no.A814. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a group of men participating in the quarter-mile race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. Six men leap forward from the start line for the race. Spectators look on from the left; note the parasols some of the women hold. The man at the far right and the man at the far left are probably race officials. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 814 for print of this negative.
  - Participants in relay race, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 815)
    Negative no.A815. August 12, 1916. Image depicts men participating in a relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man hands off to his partner in the center. Another runner is to the left, while a fourth man can be seen racing in the background. Spectators line the course on from the left; note the parasols some of the women hold. The men at the far right are probably race officials. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 815 for print of this negative.
  - Hurdle race, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 816)
    Negative no.A816. August 12, 1916. Image depicts runners participating in a hurdle race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man has just cleared one of the hurdles in the center right, while another leaps toward a hurdle on the left. A third runner can be seen racing up to the hurdles. Scattered spectators watch the race. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 804 and Negative 817, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 816 for print of this negative.
  - Hurdle race, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 817)
    Negative no.A817. August 12, 1916. Image depicts runners participating in a hurdle race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. One man has just cleared one of the hurdles on the far left while another approaches on the left. Two more runners approach the hurdles in the center. The men on either side of the course in straw hats and jackets are probably race officials. A few scattered spectators watch in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 804 and Negative 816, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 817 for print of this negative.
  - Broad jump, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 818)
    Negative no.A818. August 12, 1916. Image depicts a participant in a broad jump contest, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The jumper has just landed and an official stands by to measure his jump, while other officials look on. Spectators watch in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 818 for print of this negative.
  - Race finish, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 819)
    Negative no.A819. August 12, 1916. Image depicts runners finishing a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. It is unknown which race it is, but the man on the left in the dark shirt raises his arms in triumph as he hits the line being held at the finish line. Another runner matches him stride for stride, while two more runners can be seen further back. A crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left. The man in the dark shirt can also be seen in Box 47, Negative 823. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 819 for print of this negative.
  - Race participants, 1916 (Box 46, Folder 820)
    Negative no.A820. August 12, 1916. Image depicts five male runners participating in a race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. It is unknown which race it is, but the men are charging forward. A crowd of spectators watches from the side of the course on the left; note the number of parasols being held by some women. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 2, Item 820 for print of this negative.
  - Shop Dept. - Wet Hose competition, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 901)
    Negative no.A901. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men, presumably employees of the Draper Corporation shop dept., handling a wet hose as part of some sort of competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Company for Draper Company employees. The man in the straw hat, kneeling behind the competitors, is an official of some kind. Spectators (mostly young boys) look on behind. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 912, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 901 for print of this negative.
  - Lawn tennis doubles, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 902)
    Negative no.A902. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two men are in the far court (one is in the backcourt, in the extreme left background) and a third man is in the near court. The fourth player is presumably out of camera range on the right. Some spectators watch from the far side of the court in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 903, in this box, Negative 917, in this box, and Box 52,, Negative 921. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 902 for print of this negative.
  - Lawn tennis doubles, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 903)
    Negative no.A903. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two men are in the far court (one is in the backcourt, in the left background) and a third man is in the near court. The fourth player is presumably out of camera range on the right. The man in the near court has his right arm pulled back, about to return the ball. Some spectators watch from the far side of the court in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 902 and Negative 917, and Box 52, Negative 921. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 903 for print of this negative.
  - Woman throwing baseball, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 904)
    Negative no.A904. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a woman throwing a baseball in front of a crowd, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The woman is wearing a white dress, white stockings and white shoes, and is hatless. All of the spectators in the background are boys and men, including one man in a baseball uniform, and one man in a police uniform. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 905 and Negative 906, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 904 for print of this negative.
  - Woman throwing baseball, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 905)
    Negative no.A905. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a woman throwing a baseball in front of a crowd, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The woman is wearing a medium-colored dress with a white collar and white cuffs, dark stockings and shoes, and is wearing a straw hat. She is wearing a necklace and rimless glasses. All of the spectators in the background are boys and men, including two men in baseball uniforms. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 904 and Negative 906, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 905 for print of this negative.
  - Woman throwing baseball, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 906)
    Negative no.A906. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a woman throwing a baseball in front of a crowd, most likely part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The woman is wearing a white dress with a "sailor" collar, white stockings and shoes, and a white cloche hat. All of the spectators in the background are boys and men, including one man in a baseball uniform and one man in a policeman's uniform. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 904 and Negative 905, in this box. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 906 for print of this negative.
  - Participant in shot-put competition, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 907)
    Negative no.A907. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a man participating in a shot- put competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man has just hurled the shot-put out of camera range. The man in the straw hat on the extreme left and the man in the white shirt standing behind the competitor are both officials of some kind. Male and female spectators line the side of the field. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 908, in this box, which shows a different competitor. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 907 for print of this negative.
  - Participant in shot-put competition, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 908)
    Negative no.A908. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a man participating in a shot- put competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man (in the foreground) has just hurled the shot-put out of camera range. The man in the straw hat on the extreme left, the man in the white shirt standing in the center behind the competitor, and the man in suit and tie with a straw hat next to him are all officials of some kind. Another competitor stands to wait his turn. Male and female spectators line the side of the field in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 907, in this box, which shows a different competitor. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 908 for print of this negative.
  - Start of the 220-yard dash, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 909)
    Negative no.A909. August 9, 1919. Image depicts male runners at the start of the 220-yard dash, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Eight men burst forth from the starting line in the foreground. An official of some sort stands behind them. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also, Box 52, Negative 926. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 909 for print of this negative.
  - Finish of half-mile race, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 910)
    Negative no.A910. August 9, 1919. Image depicts male runner finishing the half-mile race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The male runner is just crossing the finish line; no other runners are in sight. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 910 for print of this negative.
  - Fire Dept. relay race, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 911)
    Negative no.A911. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two male runners handing off a baton in the Fire Dept. relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. It is presumed that these are members of the fire dept. of the Draper Corporation and not the Hopedale Fire Dept., but it is possible that town employees competed against Draper Corp. employees. The man with his back to the camera, behind the runner, is most likely an official. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 911 for print of this negative.
  - Shop Dept.: Wet Hose competition, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 912)
    Negative no.A912. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men, presumably employees of the Draper Corporation shop dept., handling a wet hose as part of some sort of competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Spectators (mostly young boys) look on behind. See also Negative 901, in this box, but the men seem to have a better grip on the hose in this image. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 912 for print of this negative.
  - Shop Dept. relay race, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 913)
    Negative no.A913. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two male runners on the left handing off a baton in the Draper Corporation shop dept. relay race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. In the center, another runner waits for his relay partner to arrive. A fourth runner is off to the side on the right. Spectators, both men and women, line the side of the course. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 913 for print of this negative.
  - 50-yard girls' race, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 914)
    Negative no.A914. August 9, 1919. Image depicts a group of girls taking part in the 50-yard girls' race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Some spectators can be seen in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 914 for print of this negative.
  - Finish, 100-yard dash, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 915)
    Negative no.A915. August 9, 1919. Image depicts the finish of the 100-yard dash that took place, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Several men race to the finish line, with two crossing the line at approximately the same spot; two more men are behind them. Spectators line the race course, mostly men near the finish but many ladies can be seen further away. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 915 for print of this negative.
  - Town Dept.: Wet Hose competition, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 916)
    Negative no.A916. August 9, 1919. Image depicts two men handling a wet hose as part of some sort of competition, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The man in the straw hat, kneeling off to the right, is an official of some kind (he is also seen in Negative 901, in this box). Spectators (mostly young boys) look on behind. It is unclear if "town dept." refers to a dept. of some sort in the Draper Corporation, or whether these were town employees competing against Draper employees--see Negative 901, in this box, for the "Shop Dept." participating in the same competition. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 916 for print of this negative.
  - Lawn tennis doubles, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 917)
    Negative no.A917. August 9, 1919. Image depicts men playing doubles tennis, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. Two of the men are in the far court (one close to the net, the other in the back court), while one man is positioned in the near court, close to the net. The fourth player is not visible but may be in the backcourt on the right out of the photographer's range. Spectators watch from the sidelines in the background. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Negative 902 and Negative 903, in this box, and Box 52, Negative 921. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 917 for print of this negative.
  - Spoon and Potato Race, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 918)
    Negative no.A918. August 9, 1919. Image depicts three women participating in a spoon and potato race, most likely as part of a "Field Day" organized by the Draper Corporation for Draper Corporation employees. The general idea is presumably to be the first to get your potato to a designated area (probably the boxes on the far left) and whichever box fills first wins the race. A crowd of spectators watches in the background. This does not appear to be the same race as the girls' potato race, shown in Negative 919 and Negative 920, in this box. Founders of the Draper Company, brothers George and Ebenezer, were responsible for creating an integrated, planned community with innovative employee housing and recreational spaces and company events, in addition to employment. See also Box 52, Negative 923. 5 x 7 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 5, Folder 5, Item 918 for print of this negative.
  - Girls Potato Race, 1919 (Box 51, Folder 919)